<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ellie Marvin</title>
    <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ellie Marvin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week12/</guid>
      <description>Time: 30 minutes
For this week&#39;s exercise, I am sharing a few cleaned-up versions of texts generated by GPT-2. These .txt files have been linked to this page via GitHub and can be downloaded directly from GitHub.
Most of these texts came from NaNoGenMo is a twist on the popular NaNoWriMo&amp;ndash;or, National Novel Writing Month&amp;ndash;in which partcipants aim to generate 50,000 words of text using whatever coding, AI, or scripting they can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week10/</guid>
      <description>Time: 30 minutes
This week I focused on finally launching my site. I could not figure out how to connect my Jekyll site to my GitHub pages site, so I switched instead to Hugo. After many hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to connect Hugo to Netlify via GitHub. After successfully deploying a site to host the samples generated by SAIGE, a model of GPT-2 trained on a corpus of Surrealist literature, I applied the same technique to a site for my Comp Methods GitHub repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week11/</guid>
      <description>This week I focused on finally launching my site. I could not figure out how to connect my Jekyll site to my GitHub pages site, so I switched instead to Hugo. After many hours of trial and error, I finally figured out how to connect Hugo to Netlify via GitHub. Here is my first post. I will be populating this site as the course continues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week9/</guid>
      <description>Time: 4 1/2 hours
I downloaded the TopicModelingTool and dove right in. Immediately I noticed there was one issue that was skewing all of my results. The sizes (word counts) of all of my sources were dramatically different, so I would have to figure out a way to compare them on a more accurate scale. I discovered that the Documents tab shows the topics based on a percentage, rather than a word count, which is much better for me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week8/</guid>
      <description>Time: 12 hours
I forgot to write something up for this exercise so I&#39;m going back retroactively. I was ill for most of lask week (got tested and it wasn&#39;t COVID, so it must have just been a horrible cold or the flu&amp;ndash;my roommate works at a hospital so who knows) but luckily had started working on this assignment the day after it was introduced. I&#39;ve worked with Hugo successfully in the past but not without difficulties and assumed (correctly) that Jekyll would be just as difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week7/</guid>
      <description>Time: 2 hours
I had a lot of trouble with getting Chocolatey to work (I guess my laptop is too old, which is fair) so I ended up installing RubyGems directly from the site (which required a separate installer and was very annoying). Once I got RubyGems and Jekyll installed, it was relatively smooth sailing. I really hate the blog-style format of this site. Like, a lot.
Then I ran into an error when trying to publish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week4/</guid>
      <description>Time: about 3 hours
For this week&#39;s exercise, I used regular expressions to detect all of the named people in Corpus S. I&#39;ve noticed, while cleaning OCR, that Surrealist text seems to directly name many Surrealists and other influential figures. I wanted to see if that theory was true. I used the following regex:
([A-Z][a-z]*) +([A-Z][a-z]*)on RegExr to find all of the phrases that contained two capitalized words in each of the text files in Corpus S.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week3/</guid>
      <description>All of the texts in Corpus AI and some of the texts in Corpus S were cleaned using regular expressions. Here&#39;s an example of my cleaning process:
Output from Tesseract:
accordion. The broom-seller’s heart froze with terror. The green sun and thetears—also green—which extended as far as the eye could see, made itperfectly clear what lilypad fate awaited him. He could not resign himself tofloating indefinitely on a sea of tears, even if it meant he would bloom withlarge flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week2/</guid>
      <description>Time: about 6 1/2 hours
I am working with two separate corpora for copyright and size purposes. The first, smaller corpus will be referred to as Corpus S (for Surrealism) and the second, larger corpus will be referred to as Corpus AI (for Artificial Intelligence).
Corpus S is something I’ve been assembling for a while now. It includes a variety of novels, poems, essays, and a screenplay. My intention for this is to train GPT-2 (an AI from OpenAI) on this corpus to generate Surrealist (or otherwise interesting) text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1</title>
      <link>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 17:56:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cm21.netlify.app/posts/week1/</guid>
      <description>Time: about 90 minutes
For this exercise, I chose to work with some data that will factor into the corpus I’m using to train GPT-2 for my Master’s project. The data is an excerpt from a book of poetry, Paul Eluard’s Letters to Gala. This text has a table at the beginning of it of the chronology of Eluard and Gala’s lives. Since the text is not in the public domain, I used scans from a copy of the text and ran them through Tesseract, an OCR software.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>